Shelenkov Anton Mikhailovich

Java developer

Moscow, Russia +7-926-534-26-61 anshelen@yandex.ru https://github.com/Anshelen

https://shelenkov.herokuapp.com/



Summary:

I have 1.5 years of experience in software development as a Java backend developer. Also was involved in front-end development (JavaScript / HTML / CSS). I have knowledge of Python 3 and practice in blockchain development (Ethereum) where I have written a few smart contracts in Solidity language.

I have good verbal and written English skills at upper-intermediate level (have FCE certificate). Had experience in project management and leading a team with 2 more developers. As part of that project, I worked with tasks using Redmine, made a code review.

Skills:

- Confident knowledge of Java SE 8, Collections Framework, Concurrency
- Knowledge of algorithms and data structures, understanding of OOP and client-server architecture
- Experience with Spring (Spring Core, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Spring Security, Spring Data JPA)
- Confident knowledge of Hibernate, experience in organizing audit using Hibernate Envers and tuning full-text search with Hibernate Search
- Experience with PostgreSQL, writing SQL queries, using PL/SQL
- Experience in using view generation technologies: Thymeleaf, Apache Wicket, Zk Framework, JSP
- Test-driven development (TDD) using JUnit, Mockito, Selenium
- Experience in web technologies JavaScript, ¡Query, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 4
- Build projects with Maven, continuous integration configuration using Git, Travis and Heroku
- Profiling Java applications
- Using Python 3 for scripting
- Understanding of Ethereum blockchain, smart-contracts development in Solidity language, experience in using Web3j library

Experience:

Java developer at «IQManager» (October 2018 – July 2019) – 10 months. I worked unofficially part-time, combining with study in university. I supported and improved the site for organizing events (https://igmanager.org/). Some of the tasks I have completed:

- Integration with Sberbank acquiring system, implemented partial payments and automatic refunds
- I profiled admin panel and eliminated performance bottlenecks. It reduced the loading time of some pages by an order of magnitude
- Added and customized Google Maps to improve the user experience in interacting with the delivery system

Intern programmer at «Simplex Software» (November 2017 – September 2018) – 9 months. I worked part-time, combining with study in university. Some of projects I took part in:

- 1. Arbitr parser of administrative cases card-file. I was entrusted with leading the development of this project. Some of my tasks and challenges:
 - Integration with Rucaptcha.com (captcha recognition service)
 - Design a multi-threaded system
- 2. Talksift (http://talksift.ru/) discussion forum
 - Develop a rating review system so that users can quickly respond to changes in disputes
 - Work with large SQL queries (about 100 rows) in order to improve filters
- 3. PajCoin (https://www.pajcoin.com/) Ethereum-based token with smart contract acting as an exchanger
 - Token and smart contract development
 - Integration with Oraclize oracle
 - Development of specialized oracle for using it instead of Oraclize. It reduced transaction costs and, as a result, the exchanger commission by 4 times

Education:

Bauman Moscow State University. Master degree in "Air conditioning systems" (2013 - 2019)

Additional education:

«Algorithms: theory and practice. Methods» course – certificate https://stepik.org/cert/187216

«Algorithms: theory and practice. Data structures» course – certificate https://stepik.org/cert/194175